<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Laura C.</title>
    <link>https://laz08.github.io/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Laura C.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://laz08.github.io/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulating a Fake News Epidemic</title>
      <link>https://laz08.github.io/projects/fake-news-proj/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laz08.github.io/projects/fake-news-proj/</guid>
      <description>This project is a joint work done with:
 Carolina Jorge Centeio Kymry Burwell  About The motivation of this project has been to study how Fake news spread and whether we were able to create an epidemic SI model to recreate it.
This study was done as an assignment for the subject called Complex and Social Networks (CSN) for Facultat d&amp;rsquo;Informatica de Barcelona at Universitat Politecnica de Catalunya (FIB - UPC).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image Gender Classification using KNN, SVM and CNN</title>
      <link>https://laz08.github.io/projects/image-gender-classification/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laz08.github.io/projects/image-gender-classification/</guid>
      <description>(or, without applying acronyms, K Nearest Neighbors, Support Vector Machines and Convolutional Neural Networks methods.)
Authors This project is a joint work done with my friends and colleagues:
 Carles Garriga. (Contact him) Balbina Virgili. (Contact her) Me.  About The motivation of this project is derived from multiple factors.
To summarize, we have always worked with numerical or categorical data. But having technology nowadays such as Facial recognition, we asked ourselves: how does machine learning work applied to images?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study on vehicles accidents occurred in UK, 2016</title>
      <link>https://laz08.github.io/projects/uk-accidents-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laz08.github.io/projects/uk-accidents-study/</guid>
      <description>This project is a joint work done with my friend and colleague Carles G.. (Contact him)
About The motivation of this project has been to study why and how the accidents in the UK occur, taking into account the circumstances, casualties and vehicles involved.
This study was done as an assignment for the subject called Algorithmics for Data Mining (ADM) for Facultat d&amp;rsquo;Informatica de Barcelona at Universitat Politecnica de Catalunya (FIB - UPC).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>American Comics&#39; Characters Data Visualization Analysis</title>
      <link>https://laz08.github.io/projects/american-comics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laz08.github.io/projects/american-comics/</guid>
      <description>This (small) project aims to do a small analysis on American comics&amp;rsquo; superheroes and see if the characters most popular have any similar characteristics that makes them as such.
Motivation Although not a fan of superheroes, the theme and topic was interesting. Mainly, I was interested on seeing if all the main characters in western comics follow any trend / share any traits.
This project was done as an assignment for the subject called Data Analysis and Knowledge discovery (DAKD) for Facultat d&amp;rsquo;Informatica de Barcelona at Universitat Politecnica de Catalunya (FIB - UPC).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data and Images Compression</title>
      <link>https://laz08.github.io/projects/compression/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://laz08.github.io/projects/compression/</guid>
      <description>About Several small projects were done to study data compression.
All their implementations have been done in Python.
They were assignments for the subject called Data and Images Compression (CDI) for Facultat d&amp;rsquo;Informatica de Barcelona at Universitat Politecnica de Catalunya (FIB - UPC). This subject is from the Degree in Computer Science at said university.
The projects  Natural language entropy. &amp;lt;&amp;lt; See project here &amp;gt;&amp;gt; Source coding &amp;lt;&amp;lt; See project here &amp;gt;&amp;gt;:  Shannon Shannon fano</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>